Kritika Uma Shankar

Sandy, Utah 84070 • (408) 429-9497

kritikaumashankar@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/kritikaumashankar

Focussed and quick learning Software developer with 3.5 years of experience in programming who is proficient in Java, HTML, CSS and Javascript. Bringing in depth experience in software design, maintenance, as well as the ability to work with new and existing codes.

Skills

Software:

Proficient: Java, J2EE, Javascript, SQL, React, HTML, CSS

Beginner: Spring, JSON, NodeJS(Express), PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST API, Spring Boot,

JPA/Hibernate.

Tools: Tortoise SVN, Eclipse IDE, IntelliJ IDEA, Git, Heroku, AWS(S3 Bucket), Visual Studio Code,

Sublime Text, Apache Tomcat, Apache Maven.

Experience

Senior System Engineer

Apr 2013 - Jun 2014

Infosys Ltd., Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Technologies: Java, Struts, JSP, MS SQL, Javascript, SVN, HTML, CSS, Oracle

- Collaborated with the on-site team member to understand the business process, gathered
 requirements, analyzed and created the technical design document for Bulk Email
 application (Bank Of America client) where different email template is created for different
 downstream applications.
- A scheduler job was implemented to store User view, Email click in database from XML in Java.
- Enhanced and added new functionality to the existing application for better UI usage to improve user experience.

System Engineer

Dec 2010 - Mar 2013

Infosys Ltd., Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Technologies: Java, Struts, JSP, DB2, Springs, SVN, Javascript, EJB, SOAP

- Involved in Analysis, Build and Test phase of enterprise application called **Express Pass** (American Express client).
- Optimized the performance of the application by writing DB queries into Stored Procedures.
- Integrated Spring(Dependency Injection) into the application as a POC. Received appreciation from Team Lead and Project Manager after successfully completing it.
- Responsible for post production support and maintenance.

Education

• The University of Utah, Professional Education, Salt Lake City, Utah Full-time Web Development Certificate, DevPoint Labs

Aug 2018 - Oct 2018

K C G College Of Technology, Anna University, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India
 Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical and Electronics
 Sept 2006 - May 2010

Projects

Enterprise International:

Sep 2018 - Oct 2018

- Developed by a team of 5 people as part of final project during bootcamp.
- Technologies: React, styled-component, Semantic, Rails, PostgreSQL
- Designed and developed Destinations(for both normal and admin user), Contact Us, Register pages.

Portfolio Website: Oct 2018 - Present

www.iamkritika.live

- Developed in React for front-end and Node.js for BackEnd.
- MongoDB is used to store number of clicks.
- Nodemailer for sending email.
- Used GitHub API for displaying the projects in Work section.

Magic 8 Ball: Mar 2019 - Apr 2019

github.com/kritikaumashankar/Magic8BallRestJava

- Developed in Java and REST(Jersey).
- Ask a question and random answer is displayed.
- List, add, edit and delete the answer.

Flash Cards Apr 2019 - Jun 2019

https://flashcardsfullstack.herokuapp.com/

- FrontEnd is developed in React. Back End is developed in RESTful and Spring Boot.
- A simple webapp to play flash card game where questions will be displayed and you can guess the answer.
- Question and Answers can be added, edited or deleted. There is a time interval of 5s to display next question and questions are displayed randomly.